<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sanchit Pathak</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sanchit Pathak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/linux/</guid>
      <description>Top Linux Commands
find: Search for files and directories based on various criteria. find /path/to/search -name &amp;#34;*.txt&amp;#34; grep: Use advanced patterns and options for searching text. grep -E &amp;#34;pattern1|pattern2&amp;#34; file.txt awk: A powerful text processing tool for extracting and manipulating data. awk &amp;#39;{print $1}&amp;#39; file.txt sed: Stream editor for modifying text using patterns. sed &amp;#39;s/search/replace/&amp;#39; file.txt tar: Create or extract compressed archive files. tar -czvf archive.tar.gz /path/to/directory rsync: Synchronize files and directories between two locations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I have a profound passion for tackling complex challenges in cloud infrastructure across diverse platforms. My expertise revolves around leveraging Infrastructure as Code tools like Terraform, Ansible, and Saltstack, coupled with CI/CD pipelines. I excel in Docker, Kubernetes, and other cutting-edge technologies, embracing cloud-native and agile principles wholeheartedly. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been delving deeper into Data Structures and Algorithms, enhancing my proficiency in Python and Bash scripting along the way.
Currently working as a Cloud Operations Engineer at Platform9 Systems with overall experience of 5 years in this domain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps CI/CD Project for Distributed Microservice Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/azure-devops-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/azure-devops-cicd/</guid>
      <description>Azure DevOps is a suite of services provided by Microsoft Azure that allows teams to plan projects, collaborate on code development, and deploy applications. It includes services like Azure Repos for version control, Azure Pipelines for continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD), Azure Boards for project management, Azure Artifacts for package management, and Azure Test Plans for test management.
Overall, it provides a comprehensive set of tools for software development and delivery, supporting agile practices and DevOps principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EBS Volume GP2 to GP3 Conversion using a CloudWatch Events Triggered Lambda Function</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ebs-volume-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ebs-volume-conversion/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I am going over how to automate the conversion of EBS volumes from the GP2 type to GP3 by using CloudWatch Events to trigger a Lambda function upon volume creation ensuring that new volumes are automatically optimized.
For a 2000 GB volume with approximate usage of 12 hours in a month, the charges for GP3 will be $2.667 and for GP2 it will be $3.33. Reference: EBS-Pricing</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EKS Cluster Provisioning with VPC Configuration using Terraform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/eks-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/eks-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Terraform&amp;rsquo;s declarative approach allows to describe the infrastructure in a high-level manner where it evaluates the current state of the infrastructure and determines what actions need to be taken to reach the desired state. Also, its idempotent nature means that applying the same configuration multiple times will result in the same end state as applying it once.
In this blog post I am going over how to setup EKS cluster using Terraform including all the pre-requistites of setting up VPC, SG etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/k8s/</guid>
      <description>Create a Job which prints output $ kubectl create job hello --image=busybox:1.28 -- echo &amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34; Create a CronJob that prints Hello World every minute kubectl create cronjob hello --image=busybox:1.28 --schedule=&amp;#34;*/1 * * * *&amp;#34; -- echo &amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34; Get all running pods in the namespace kubectl get pods --field-selector=status.phase=Running Check which nodes are ready JSONPATH=&amp;#39;{range .items[*]}{@.metadata.name}:{range @.status.conditions[*]}{@.type}={@.status};{end}{end}&amp;#39; \ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; kubectl get nodes -o jsonpath=&amp;#34;$JSONPATH&amp;#34; | grep &amp;#34;Ready=True&amp;#34; List Events sorted by timestamp kubectl get events --sort-by=.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
